Donald F. Carmony papers, 1949-1984 C4
Indiana University Archives
Donald F. Carmony papers
1949-1984
1955-1980
Indiana University Archives
Carmony, Donald F. (Donald Francis)
C4
7.6 cubic feet
Donald F. Carmony was an Indiana historian; member of the Indiana University faculty, 1939-1980; Director of the IU South Bend Extension Center, 1944-1950; Associate Dean of the IU Extension Division, 1950-1959; and editor of the Indiana Magazine of History, 1955-1975. His collection consists of correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes, and other materials relating to History Department of Indiana University; university committees; professional, state, and local organizations, notably the American Association of State and Local History, Bloomington-Monroe County Bicentennial Commission, and New Harmony Plan Commission; and general correspondence with faculty, administrators, and the public, much of which deals with historic preservation issues. Does not include research notes or teaching materials.
Access Restrictions
Select files are closed to researchers. These are indicated in the finding aid.
Advance notice is required for access.
Biographical Note
Donald F. Carmony was born in 1910 in Shelby County, Indiana and spent his formative years on a farm. He attended Indiana Central College (now the University of Indianapolis), graduating in 1929 with his A.B. While working on his Ph.D. in history at Indiana University he taught history at Indiana Central College, receiving his doctorate in 1940.
In the summer of 1939 Carmony taught at Butler University following which he was appointed and served as the first full time history faculty member at the Indiana University Fort Wayne Extension Center. From 1944 to 1950 Carmony served as the director of the South Bend Extension Center and was appointed Associate Dean of the Extension Division in 1950 where he served until February 1st, 1959.
Following his departure from the Extension Center he became a full time member of the history faculty on the Bloomington campus. Carmony remained on the history faculty until his retirement in 1980, serving as chair of the department during the summer of 1962. Carmony's area of expertise was Indiana history, and from 1955 to 1975 he edited the Indiana Magazine of History.
During his academic career Carmony was active on several university committees, including the Cornelius O'Brien lecture series, the Committee on Historic Preservation, the Indiana University Sesquicentennial Committee, and the Committee on the Career Status of Librarians. Carmony also served on several committees within the history department, most prominently the Executive Committee.
Outside of the university, Carmony took an active role in local and state programs, including serving as chair of the Indiana Sesquicentennial Commission (no records in collection) and chair for the Great Books program in Indiana in the late 1940s and early 1950s. He was also an active member of the American Association for State and Local History, Bloomington Bicentennial Commission, and New Harmony Commission, among many others.
Among the five books published by Carmony are Indiana: from Frontier to Industrial Commonwealth (1954), and Indiana 1816-1850: The Pioneer Era (1988), widely considered as one of the definitive studies of Hoosier pioneer life. In 1998 Carmony was named a Sagamore of the Wabash by Governor Frank O'Bannon, and in 2001 he became only the sixth individual to be named an honorary life member of the Society of Indiana Pioneers. Carmony died on February 14, 2005 at the age of 95.
Scope and Content Note
Donald Carmony donated his papers to the University Archives in 1983 and 1984. The collection relates to Carmony's work as a member of the Indiana University faculty and to his activities as a member of University and community committees. The collection comprises 7.6 cubic feet and dates from 1949 to 1984, with the bulk of the material falling between 1955 and 1980. Prominent types of materials in the collection include correspondence, reports, memoranda, and clippings.
The first series, General correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by surname. Materials date from 1949 to 1984 with the bulk of the correspondence falling between 1955 and 1980. Correspondents in the general correspondence files include faculty members at Indiana University, especially within the history department, faculty at the extension centers, deans of the university, university presidents Herman B Wells and John Ryan, scholars such as Robert M. Utley, staff at historical societies, citizens of Indiana, publishers, former students, and elementary school students. There is little correspondence with family members. Correspondence relating to committees and outside organizations can be found in IU Committee, and Outside organizations series.
Indiana University is the second series and spans the years from 1955 to 1983. It is further organized into four subseries: History Department, History Department Committees, IU Committees, and IU Subject Files, with each subseries arranged alphabetically. The History Department subseries includes departmental meeting minutes, various undergraduate and graduate student program materials, and faculty annual and summary reports. History Department Committees includes Advisory Committee materials, and Executive Committee and Policy Committee meeting minutes. IU Committees contains materials concerning the American Revolution Bicentennial, Historic Preservation, Heritage, IU Sesquicentennial, and Professional Status of Librarians c ommittees. Finally, IU Subject Files includes materials on the Buley memorial, the Dow Chemical student protest in the fall of 1967, and Carmony's retirement in 1980.
The third series, Outside organizations, consists of materials from organizations not connected with Indiana University. It is arranged into ten subseries: Adult Education Association; American Association of State and Local History; Bloomington Bicentennial Commission; Commission on Higher Education; Hoosier History Committee; Indiana History Panel / Indiana Higher Education Telecommunication System; National Conference of Christians and Jews; NDEA; New Harmony Commission; and State Social Studies Curriculum Revision Committee. Outside organizations series is arranged alphabetically by organization name and dates ranging from 1956 to 1981. The subseries are also arranged alphabetically.
The fourth series is Great Books. It is arranged into four subseries: Clinics; Alphabetical files; City files; and Leader files, and consists of materials from the 1940s to 1973. The subseries and their arrangement are derived from the original order; Clinics is arranged chronologically, while the other three are arranged alphabetically. Clinics consists primarily of correspondence and bulletins regarding the yearly training clinics for group leaders held by the Indiana Great Books program. Alphabetical files includes correspondence and subject files while City files contains annual reports from Great Books groups in Indiana; it is arranged by city name. Finally, Leader files consists of materials Carmony used to lead Great Books meetings on select works and is arranged by the author's last name. Although Great Books could logically be part of Outside organizations, its size and depth require it to be its own series.
Subject files makes up the last series; it spans the years from 1953 to 1983 and is also arranged alphabetically. It consists of awards and newspaper clippings about Carmony, history bibliographies, materials on the Hershey Library and river trails in Southern Indiana, and Hubert Humphrey campaign materials from Carmony's involvement in the campaign.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into five series: General correspondence; Indiana University; Outside organizations; Great Books; and Subject files.
Separated Material
Four cubic feet of materials were removed from the Carmony collection and transferred to the University Publications Series.
Photographs have been transferred to the Archives Photographs collection.
Related Material
For records relating to Dr. Carmony's tenures as Director of the South Bend Extension Center and Associate Dean for the Extension Division see Archives Collection C13.
For records relating to his chairmanship of the University Committee on Historic Preservation see Collection C30.
Acquisition Information
Accessions 0539, 95/008, and 2004/128.
American Revolution Bicentennial, 1776-1976 --Indiana --Monroe County --History --Sources.; Historic preservation --Indiana.; Historians --Indiana --Bloomington --Archives.; Historians --Indiana --Bloomington --Correspondence.; American Association for State and Local History; Bloomington-Monroe County Bicentennial Commission; New Harmony (Ind.). Plan Commission; Carmony, Donald F. (Donald Francis) -- Archives; Carmony, Donald F. (Donald Francis) -- Correspondence; Indiana University, Bloomington. Department of History -- History -- 20th century -- Sources
- General correspondence, 1949-1984; undated
  - Achor, Judge Harold E., 1961-1966 (Box 1)
  - Aeschbacher, William D., 1959-1964 (Box 1)
  - Alderson, William T., 1964-1974 (Box 1)
  - Allen, Michael, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Jayme, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Appleton, Eileen, 1961-1972 (Box 1)
  - Appleton, Thomas H., 1983 (Box 1)
  - Armstrong, William S., 1962; 1967 (Box 1)
  - Ashton, J.W., 1963 (Box 1)
  - Austen, Allen, 1962 (Box 1)
  - A General file (Box 1)
    - Able, Tim, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Adams, Mr. and Mrs. James D., 1965 (Box 1)
    - Albertson, Dean, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Alderfer, Dr. William K., 1968 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Carol (Mrs. Bewley), 1972 (Box 1)
    - Allen, David P., 1978 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Max P., 1960 (Box 1)
    - Allworth, Carolyn C., 1971 (Box 1)
    - Andressohn, John C., 1955 (Box 1)
    - Andrews, James R., 1979 (Box 1)
    - Annakin, V. Dewey, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Anness, Milford E., 1966 (Box 1)
    - Ansberry, W.F., 1963 (Box 1)
    - Anson, Bert, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Anthony, Dr. Cloyd, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Antisdel, Lewis A., 1963 (Box 1)
    - Arensmen, Dr. Ray W., 1960 (Box 1)
    - Armstrong, E. Clifford, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Aton, Melissa, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Averitt, Will F., 1966 (Box 1)
  - Ball, Edmund F., 1971; 1978 (Box 1)
  - Bard, Harriet, 1964-1979 (Box 1)
  - Barnhart, John D., 1948-1958 (Box 1)
  - Bartley, E. Ross, 1959-1967 (Box 1)
  - Batchelor, Joseph, 1960; 1961 (Box 1)
  - Baxter, Maurice, 1960-1980 (Box 1)
  - Bayh, Birch, 1967-1979 (Box 1)
  - Bearss, Edwin C., 1967; 1969 (Box 1)
  - Beckes, Isaac K., 1961-1984 (Box 1)
  - Berhardt-Kabisch, Ernest, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Billington, Ray, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Blake, George and F. Brances, 1930-1966; undated (Box 1)
  - Bogle, Victor M., 1960-1977 (Box 1)
  - Bolling, Landrum, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Bowman, Sylvia, 1959-1968 (Box 1)
  - Braeman, John, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Bray, William G., 1966-1974 (Box 1)
  - Brooks, G., 1974; 1975 (Box 1)
  - Broyles, Ralph E., 1961-1974 (Box 1)
  - Buehrig, Edward, 1949-1950 (Box 1)
  - Buhner, John C., 1960-1978 (Box 1)
  - Buley, R.C., 1964-1967 (Box 1)
  - Byrd, Cecil, 1950-1971 (Box 1)
  - Byrnes, Robert F., 1958-1964 (Box 1)
  - B General file (Box 1)
    - Babcock, Glen, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Backer, Dr. and Mrs. Joseph, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Bailey, J.J., 1963 (Box 1)
    - Baker, Harry J., 1968 (Box 1)
    - Baker, Marry B., 1970 (Box 1)
    - Baldwin, Caroline Dale-Owen S., 1971 (Box 1)
    - Ball, Will, 1954 (Box 1)
    - Banta, Richard E., 1964 (Box 1)
    - Banton, Albert W., 1968 (Box 1)
    - Barber, Dr. C.L., 1963 (Box 1)
    - Barnard, Dorothy, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Barnhart, Larry, 1961 (Box 1)
    - Barroll, J. Leeds, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Barton, Joseph J., 1976 (Box 1)
    - Batchelder, Dr. Howard T., 1954 (Box 1)
    - Baughman, John J., 1975 (Box 1)
    - Beall, Mary Ellen, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Bedal, Mrs. E.D., 1961 (Box 1)
    - Bell, Dr. Frank, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Benes, Vaclav L., 1963 (Box 1)
    - Beril, Richard P., 1968 (Box 1)
    - Berthrong, Donald J., 1979 (Box 1)
    - Besch, Dr. Henry R., Jr., 1979 (Box 1)
    - Biehl, Lois, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Billings, Mr. and Mrs. Claude, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Blackwelder, Mrs. Memory F., 1963 (Box 1)
    - Blair, Don, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Blessinger, Thomas E., 1964 (Box 1)
    - Blue, G.M., 1966 (Box 1)
    - Blue, Merle, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Bottorff, Richard L., 1964 (Box 1)
    - Bovie, Dr. S. Palmer, 1961 (Box 1)
    - Bowen, Otis R., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Bowman, L. Michael, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Boyer, Paul, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Brand, Jancie, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Brandenburg, Eva and Craig, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Branigan, Roger D., 1968 (Box 1)
    - Bremke, Sister Mary Ann, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Brenneman, Burton F., 1965 (Box 1)
    - Briscoe, Herman T., 1960 (Box 1)
    - Brown, Carl E., 1970 (Box 1)
    - Brown, Henry D., 1966 (Box 1)
    - Brown, Patricia, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Brown, Sherry, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Brown County Commissioners, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Buck, Roger C., 1976 (Box 1)
    - Bumb, Oliver C., 1976 (Box 1)
    - Burgess, Chester W., 1965 (Box 1)
    - Burgess, Dale, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Burnham, Irene U., 1977 (Box 1)
    - Buroker, Paul, 1960; 1961 (Box 1)
    - Burns, David V., 1976 (Box 1)
    - Burns, Harold E., 1959 (Box 1)
    - Burton, Robert F., 1961 (Box 1)
    - Byers, Olive S., 1968 (Box 1)
  - Campbell, Barbara K., 1961 (Box 1)
  - Carmony, Gerald C., 1961-1964 (Box 1)
    General
    (brother)
  - Carter, Byrum, 1965; 1969 (Box 1)
  - Cassidy, John A. (Box 1)
  - Chapman, Warner O., 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - Chaput, Donald, 1966-1968 (Box 1)
  - Clanin, Douglas E., 1964-1968 (Box 1)
  - Clark, Thomas D., 1962-1974 (Box 1)
  - Clemons, Kenneth, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Cloud, Joseph, 1977; 1978 (Box 1)
  - Cohen, Bill, 1974-1982 (Box 1)
  - Colbourn, Trevor, 1962-1967 (Box 1)
  - Cole, Georgia Rankin (Mrs. Herman), 1959 (Box 1)
  - Collins, Dorothy (Dottie), 1965; 1971 (Box 1)
  - Collins, Ralph, 1958-1961 (Box 1)
  - Compton, Mildred S., 1968; 1969 (Box 1)
  - Conrad, Hallie, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Cook, Margaret Ann, 1963; 1966 (Box 1)
  - Coomer, John R., 1970 (Box 1)
  - Cottman, Evans W., 1966 (Box 1)
  - Cousins, Jack, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Craig, Mary B., 1962; 1966 (Box 1)
  - Crump, Ross, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Curtis, Florence, 1962 (Box 1)
  - C General file (Box 1)
    - Caldemeyer, Richard, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Caldwell, Howard, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Campbell, Ballard, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Cammack, Eleanore, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Carleton, William G., 1977 (Box 1)
    - Carmony, Marvin, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Cartwright, Prof. William, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Cavanaugh, Rev. John J., 1963 (Box 1)
    - Chaffin, Jon R., 1967 (Box 1)
    - Chalou, George C., 1975 (Box 1)
    - Chamberlain, Edgar, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Chesebrough, Patrick E., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Christenson, Dr. Carroll L., 1964 (Box 1)
    - Clark, Dr. Vic, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Cleland, Ralph, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Clements, Robert, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Coams, Norris D., 1968 (Box 1)
    - Coats, Nelle, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Cohen, George, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Cohen, Norman S., 1966 (Box 1)
    - Coleman, Peter J., 1964 (Box 1)
    - Collings, Marie, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Collins, Mabelle, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Colwell, Kay, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Comingore, Charles E., 1965 (Box 1)
    - Conrad, Larry, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Constantine, Dr. Robert, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Cook, Kenneth J., 1961 (Box 1)
    - Coomer, John R., 1970 (Box 1)
    - Cottom, Ruth, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Coward, Robert Y., 1966 (Box 1)
    - Craig, James A., 1967 (Box 1)
    - Craver, Mrs. Samuel C., 1969 (Box 1)
    - Creakbaum, Leslie, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Creighton, Mrs. Hobart, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Cridland, Nancy C., 1977 (Box 1)
    - Crosby, Dr. Robert R., 1957 (Box 1)
    - Crouch, Wm. Jerome, 1973 (Box 1)
    - Crowder, Ralph L., 1971 (Box 1)
    - Crowe, Rep. Ray, 1974 (Box 1)
    - Crum, Maurice, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Crump, Ross G., 1969 (Box 1)
    - Cummins, Prof. Cedric, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Curtis, George M., III, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Daily, Wilson S., 1973; 1983 (Box 1)
  - Dault, R.A., 1958; 1964 (Box 1)
  - Dean, Dr. Donald I., 1956; 1960 (Box 1)
  - Dean, Everett, 1967-1969 (Box 1)
  - Deen, Floyd, 1951; 1961 (Box 1)
  - Detzer, Karl, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Detzler, Dr. Jack J., 1957-1966 (Box 1)
  - d'Haucourt, Genevieve, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Dowling, Leo R., 1959-1961 (Box 1)
  - Dubiel, Diane, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Dunn, Caroline, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - D General file (Box 1)
    - Danner, Prof. Louise, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Davidson, Frank, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Davis, Clarence, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Davis, Cullom, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Dawson, William N., 1965 (Box 1)
    - Day, H.G. (Harry), 1967 (Box 1)
    - Day, Willard J., 1960 (Box 1)
    - Decker, Mr., 1960 (Box 1)
    - Del Vecchio, Richard J., 1966 (Box 1)
    - Dennis, Thomas, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Detweiler, Prof. Philip F., 1962 (Box 1)
    - Dick, Prof. Everett, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Dineen, Clarence F., 1966 (Box 1)
    - Doherty, Rosemary Jantzen, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Dole, Prof. Philip, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Donahue, Mildred G., 1961 (Box 1)
    - Duncan, Prof. Roland, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Dunfee, Maxine, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Dunn, Joy, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Durbin, Leo, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Eddleman, Robert L., 1955; 1966 (Box 1)
  - Eldridge, James A., 1960-1967; undated (Box 1)
  - Emison, Thomas S., 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Engelland, C.W., 1961; 1965 (Box 1)
  - Engle, Dr. and Mrs. Roy, 1966; 1968 (Box 1)
  - Ewers, Joseph, 1964-1968 (Box 1)
  - E General file (Box 1)
    - Earl, Mary, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Egbert, Ercell Jane, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Ehman, John, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Eisenbarth, Robert K., 1961 (Box 1)
    - Elliott, Helen, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Elliott, Josephine, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Ellis, Frances H., 1977 (Box 1)
    - Ellis, Jay, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Elwert, Bert E., 1960 (Box 1)
    - Encyclopædia Britannica, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Endicott, Opal H., 1965 (Box 1)
    - Engle, Char, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Engle, Shirley H., 1960 (Box 1)
    - Eppley, Garrett G., 1967 (Box 1)
    - Epstein, Prof. Fritz, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Esarey, Elisha, undated (Box 1)
    - Estes, Barbara, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Everett, Helen, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Faris, Gene, 1972-1975 (Box 1)
  - Farley, Miriam S., 1973 (Box 1)
  - Feeger, Luther M., 1954-1966 (Box 1)
  - Feightner, Harold, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Ferrell, Robert, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - Field, Elsie K., 1962-1965 (Box 1)
  - Franz, Frank A., 1980; 1982 (Box 1)
  - Frederick, Robert A., 1960-1971; undated (Box 1)
  - Friedrich, Marcia, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Fuerst, Adrian (Ren), 1963; 1964 (Box 1)
  - Funk, John, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Funkhouser, Mark, 1975 (Box 1)
  - F General file (Box 1)
    - Farley, Miriam S., 1964 (Box 1)
    - Farrar, Merritt C., 1961 (Box 1)
    - Fawcett, Delos, 1961 (Box 1)
    - Fay, Prof. Leo C., 1967 (Box 1)
    - Fears, Dr. Rufus, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Feldman, Margaret L., 1960 (Box 1)
    - Fell, Arthur, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Ferrill, Everett W., 1961 (Box 1)
    - Figgins, Ruth Ann, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Fishel, Leslie H., Jr., 1961 (Box 1)
    - Fisher, Mrs. Inez, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Fitzsimmons, Allen, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Fleming, Charles, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Flynn, G.Q. (George), 1970 (Box 1)
    - Foderaro, S.J., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Foote, Marcelle K., 1968 (Box 1)
    - Forsyth, Malcolm E., 1961 (Box 1)
    - Fraenkel, Peter, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Frasier, Marie, 1960 (Box 1)
    - Freeman, Walden, 1968 (Box 1)
    - French, Denney G., 1966 (Box 1)
    - French, Pauline, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Fulton, Virginia, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Gallman, John, 1977; 1980 (Box 1)
  - Gates, Ralph F., 1966-1968 (Box 1)
  - Gibbons, Eileen, 1963-1964; undated (Box 1)
  - Giffin, William, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Gitlitz, Libby, 1975; 1980 (Box 1)
  - Glass, James, 1982; 1984 (Box 1)
  - Goodrich, Pierre, 1957; 1968 (Box 1)
  - Gordon, Michael, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Graber, Anita, 1962; 1967 (Box 1)
  - Gray, Ralph, 1969-1982 (Box 1)
  - Gros-Louis, Kenneth R.R., 1979; 1980 (Box 1)
  - Gucker, Frank, Jr., 1957; 1965 (Box 1)
  - Guthrie, Wayne, 1967-1972 (Box 1)
  - G General file (Box 1)
    - Gaither, Prof. Mary, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Galvin, John E., 1981 (Box 1)
    - Gay, Viola B., 1968 (Box 1)
    - Gellar, Sheldon, 1973 (Box 1)
    - Gemmecke, Dr. Richard, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Gill, Terry, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Gilliam, Mrs. Will D., Jr., 1976 (Box 1)
    - Gilmore, Margaret J., 1966 (Box 1)
    - Gish, Sam C., 1961 (Box 1)
    - Glick, Sally Weaver, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Glick, Susan, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Goodman, Gene B., 1966 (Box 1)
    - Goodpaster, Howard P., 1984 (Box 1)
    - Goodwin, John P., 1962 (Box 1)
    - Gordon, Rep. Robert, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Gorton, Dan W., 1968 (Box 1)
    - Goss, Jeanne Adams (Mrs. Donald D.), 1968 (Box 1)
    - Gould, George E., 1964 (Box 1)
    - Gower, Calvin W., 1970 (Box 1)
    - Graham, Dr. Loren, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Graham, Robert E., 1967 (Box 1)
    - Granger, Sharon, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Grantham, Dewey W., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Gray, Mary Alice, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Gray, Robert, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Graybar, Prof. Lloyd J., 1970 (Box 1)
    - The Great Books Foundation, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Green, Jim, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Griffin, James E., 1963 (Box 1)
    - Grimm, Prof. Harold J., 1962 (Box 1)
    - Grisby, Ms., 1982 (Box 1)
    - Gros-Louis, Delores (Dee), 1977 (Box 1)
    - Guffin, Carl, 1961 (Box 1)
    - Gunderson, Bob, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Guse, Dennis A., 1966 (Box 1)
    - Guss, Carolyn, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Guthrie, Jim, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Haffner, Gerald (Jerry), 1961-1963 (Box 1)
  - Hamilton, Holman and Susie, 1972-1980 (Box 1)
  - Hamm, JoAnn, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Hankins, Jerry J., 1963; 1965 (Box 1)
  - Hanlin, Rep. Donald, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Harding, Frances, 1967-1968 (Box 1)
  - Hasse, John, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Hawkins, Hubert H., 1955-1968 (Box 1)
  - Heffner, Ray L., Jr., 1962; 1964 (Box 1)
  - Heighway, George (Dixie), 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Heiser, Charles, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Hendricks, John, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Higgins, Smith, 1959; 1967 (Box 1)
  - Hill, John Howard, 1962-1966; 1978 (Box 1)
  - Hofstetter, Dr. Henry W., 1968-1970 (Box 1)
  - Hogue, Arthur, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Homsher, Lola, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Hopkins, George, 1964; 1965 (Box 1)
  - Hopper, Hazel, 1962-1966 (Box 1)
  - How, Beatrice, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - Hughes, Frances, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Humphreys, Frances (Mrs. Sexon E.), 1965 (Box 1)
  - Hurt, Dr. Wesley R., 1964-1982 (Box 1)
  - Hyneman, Charles S., 1965; 1982 (Box 1)
  - H General file (Box 1)
    - Hackensmith, Dr. C.W., 1970 (Box 1)
    - Hanigan, John, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Hanson, Norwood Russell, 1961 (Box 1)
    - Harmer, Bernard D., 1964 (Box 1)
    - Harmon, Mrs. M.L., 1971 (Box 1)
    - Harrington, Dan, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Harris, John, undated (Box 1)
    - Hartke, Vance, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Hartman, Charles A., 1962 (Box 1)
    - Hartman, Paul W., 1964 (Box 1)
    - Haskins, Grace E.L., 1959 (Box 1)
    - Hastings, Hon. John S., 1959 (Box 1)
    - Hattery, Robert W., 1984 (Box 1)
    - Havens, Nancy, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Haxton, Jeanette, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Hays, George A, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Hayman, Robert G., 1965 (Box 1)
    - Heath, Caroline R., 1965 (Box 1)
    - Hedges, Edward, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Hedges, Emory Donald, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Heffner, Dr. Hubert, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Heffner, Ruth Cline, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Heimlich, Herbert H., 1960 (Box 1)
    - Helfrich, Dr. Ralph William, Jr., 1965 (Box 1)
    - Heller, Dick D., Jr., 1983 (Box 1)
    - Helmke, Walter, Jr., 1978 (Box 1)
    - Henderson, Grant, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Henderson, Mrs. G.D., 1963 (Box 1)
    - Henes, John B., 1970 (Box 1)
    - Henley, George W., 1964 (Box 1)
    - Herrick, John S., 1980 (Box 1)
    - Hershey, Lillian, 1959 (Box 1)
      (To Mrs. Oscar Winther)
    - Hess, Bruce, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Hett, K. Jack, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Hibbs, Ben, 1965 (Box 1)
      (To Edward C. Von Tress)
    - Hickam, Hubert, 1975 (Box 1)